<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sparklyr on Samuel Macêdo</title>
    <link>/tags/sparklyr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sparklyr on Samuel Macêdo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sparklyr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>sparklyr: tuning your hyperparameters</title>
      <link>/2018/06/sparklyr-tuning-your-hyperparameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/sparklyr-tuning-your-hyperparameters/</guid>
      <description>Welcome, friend :)
This is another tutorial about spark using the sparklyr package. In this way, I am going to present you how tuning your model parameters. It’s not so difficult but there is some details that I have to tell you. If you are not confident about trainning your models in spark yet, check my previous post and come back here later :)
Let’s get to action…
PipelineFirst of all, you need to create a pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sparklyr: supervised learning</title>
      <link>/2018/05/sparklyr-supervised-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/sparklyr-supervised-learning/</guid>
      <description>Welcome, friend :)
In this tutorial, I am going to present you how to perform supervised learning in R using the sparklyr package. The models that I am going to use are:
Linear RegressionNaive BayesDecision TreeRandom ForestLogistic RegressionMultilayer PerceptronGradient Boosted TreeSupport Vector MachineIf you don’t know how to connect spark in R, don’t worry…check this out. If you have any question or suggestions, don’t hesitate to contact me on samuelmacedo@recife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sparklyr: connecting spark in local mode</title>
      <link>/2018/05/sparklyr-connecting-spark-in-local-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/sparklyr-connecting-spark-in-local-mode/</guid>
      <description>Welcome, friend :)
In this tutorial, I am going to present you how to connect spark with R in your local machine. This will be a very brief tutorial but you will need it to understand when you read the next tutorials about feature transformation, supervised and unsupervised learning. If you have any doubts, don’t hesitate to contact me on samuelmacedo@recife.ifpe.edu.br.
Let’s get to action… to do this task I use the sparklyr package.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>